# MAKSIM LAVRENTEV

+7 925 768 79 44

lavrentiev.max@gmail.com

Moscow / St.Petersburg, Russia linkedin.com/in/maksimlavrentev github.com/Maksim-Lavrentev

A professional in business planning and data analysis with 4 years' experience improving business operations in top FMCG and Retail companies. Ensured sustainable product supply of a \$100M/yr international business and helped identifying \$50M/yr revenue source in a new business model. Experience optimizing processes, automating routine tasks and building tools for data analysis with 50+ business users.

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

Procter&Gamble

IT PROJECT MANAGER August 2019 – March 2020

MVideoEldorado Group – top electronics retailer in Russia

Moscow, Russia

- Managed the development of a web application for e2e promo planning.
- Piloted a new change management process for the commerce department.
- Valuated and prepared high-level designs for **3 new initiatives** (marketplace expansion, services for gamers, lottery). One of the projects with additional revenue of **\$50M/yr** was **approved by CEO** for execution in 2020.

# **DEMAND PLANNER; IT PRODUCT MANAGER**

March 2017 – May 2019

Moscow, Russia

- As Oral Care Demand Planner:
  - **Increased demand forecast accuracy** in Russia to the level of Central Europe **allowing 120% YoY category growth** with supply chain optimization projects (warehouses and production plant change) and redesign of business intelligence accumulation and analysis processes.
  - Increased Case Fill Rate of electronic products (20% of business, 2x yearly growth) in hot season from 60% to 90+% by introducing a new business process with logistics and sales.
  - **Reduced workload** of Demand and Supply Planners in the region **by 1.5 FTE equivalent** by automating regular analysis tasks with new tools and dashboards (Excel, Power BI).
- As IT Product Manager:

Owned a web app for promo planning with 200+ internal & external users.

- Enabled **15% promo forecast accuracy increase** with implementation of product segmentation, new process for gifting season, reporting redesign and other improvements.
- Optimized workload of logistics managers by 6 FTE equivalent with performance and UX improvements.
- Initiated and led analysis of refactoring of the app.
- Received 1 Gold, 1 Pearl and 4 Silver Awards for innovations in promo and initiatives planning.

## **IMPLEMENTATION PROJECT MANAGER (DEMAND PLANNING)**

July 2016 - March 2017

Procter&Gamble

Moscow, Russia

Led cross-category projects on demand forecast accuracy improvement and customers' business analysis:

- Enabled 30% improvement of BI quality with a pilot of a new process and automation of analysis with Excel macros.
- The developed process and tools were fine-tuned by a global team and reapplied in other EU countries.

# JUNIOR PROJECT MANAGER (ENGINEERING)

Procter&Gamble

July-October 2015 Novomoskovsk, Russia

Conducted feasibility study of Fairy, Myth and Mr. Proper production reorganization in the largest P&G plant in Eastern Europe:

- Proposed options for relocation and optimization of bottle blowing operations.
- One of the options was executed in 2017.

#### SKILLS / KNOWLEDGE

- Data Analysis / Machine Learning: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn), MS Excel (VBA, P.Query, P.Pivot), SQL, MS Power BI
- Project Management: Atlassian Jira & Confluence, MS Project
- Domain Knowledge: Sales & Operations Planning, Demand Forecasting, Allocation & Promotion Planning in FMCG / Retail
- Language: Russian (Native), English (IELTS 8.0)

# **EDUCATION**

## 2011 - 2016 SAINT-PETERSBURG STATE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY)

BSc. Chemical Technology of Natural Energy Containers and Carbon Materials (GPA 4.9/5.0)

### HOBBIES / INTERESTS

- Bicycle Touring: around 3000 km in Finland, Portugal, Spain, France, Belgium, the Netherlands and Russia in 2018-19
- Volunteering: volunteered in several events and projects in Russia and Germany
- Online Education: numerous certificates of completion of online courses on Management and Data Science (Coursera, EdX, Stanford Online, Udacity, DataQuest)